<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Polio on Transmission Landscape</title>
    <link>https://haokaitseng.github.io/categories/polio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Polio on Transmission Landscape</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>zh-tw</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 22:11:12 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://haokaitseng.github.io/categories/polio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Mapping the Relationships: Modelling Immunisation Efforts on the Non-Polio Acute Flaccid Paralysis Rate</title>
      <link>https://haokaitseng.github.io/post/20240719_polio_poster_vaccine_hesitancy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 22:11:12 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://haokaitseng.github.io/post/20240719_polio_poster_vaccine_hesitancy/</guid>
      <description>This post shares my poster presentation at the Vaccine Hesitancy Course held by the Croucher Foundation in August, 2024, Hong Kong.&#xA;Download the poster here, which is the milestone of my thesis project at LSHTM. Introduction Global incidence of polio has decreased by 99% since 1988. Non-polio Acute Flaccid Paralysis (NPAFP) is the key indicator for the sensitivity of polio surveillance. While countries with circulating poliovirus consistently report NPAFP rates exceeding the gold-standard indicator*, it is not well-understood what rate should be expected.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Beginnig of the End: What Is the Expected Notification Rate of the Polio Surveillance Indicator?</title>
      <link>https://haokaitseng.github.io/post/20240503_polio_proposal/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 22:11:12 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://haokaitseng.github.io/post/20240503_polio_proposal/</guid>
      <description>This post presents my research proposal for my MSc thesis: &amp;ldquo;Predicting the rate of Acute Flaccid Paralysis in different settings to support polio surveillance and elimination&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;You will learn why non-polio Acute Flaccid Paralysis (NPAFP) is important in support of polio eradication. The current challenge involves interpreting the AFP indicator that exceed the targeted levels. Potential data sources and modelling methods are raised to fill this knowledge gap. Aim and Objectives Research Aim To investigate and model the mechanisms underlying the notification of the key polio surveillance indicator - NPAFP rates in endemic and outbreak settings.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
