<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vaccine on Infectious Perspectives</title>
    <link>https://haokaitseng.github.io/categories/vaccine/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Vaccine on Infectious Perspectives</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>zh-tw</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2024 22:11:12 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://haokaitseng.github.io/categories/vaccine/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Equity vs. Equality: Modelling Vaccine Distribution Strategies for Outbreak Response Decision-Making</title>
      <link>https://haokaitseng.github.io/post/20240327_modelling_flu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2024 22:11:12 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://haokaitseng.github.io/post/20240327_modelling_flu/</guid>
      <description>This group project is a collective effort, with contributions from my teammates Minn Thit Aung, Polly Nightingale, Simon Kent, and Xavier Dunn, listed alphabetically.&#xA;This post aims to:&#xA;Determine the the basic reproduction number (R0) of an hypothetical outbreak Assess the impact of various strategies for vaccination and school closures on accumulative cases and peak cases/timing Provide instructions for constructing a SEIR model using Berkeley Madonna Offer simple R code for converting a ggplot into a GIF Setting the Scene Many countries have recently experienced the first wave of an influenza pandemic caused by the strain HuNz.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assessing the Non-inferiority of the Single-dose Human Papillomavirus Vaccination Schedule: A Hypothetical Multi-country Cohort Study</title>
      <link>https://haokaitseng.github.io/post/20231216-hpv-single-dose-vaccination/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2023 22:11:12 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://haokaitseng.github.io/post/20231216-hpv-single-dose-vaccination/</guid>
      <description>What can you learn from this article? An experimental cohort study design for policy evaluation, where countries made the move from a two-dose to single-dose schedule for national HPV vaccination programmes since 2023.&#xA;Introduction Since the first licensing of the Human Papillomavirus (HPV) vaccine in 2006, evidence has been emerging showing that single-dose schedules provide comparable efficacy to the conditional regimens, i.e. two or three doses. In 2022, a review of World Health Organization (WHO) Strategic Advisory Group of Experts on Immunization (SAGE) concluded that a single-dose HPV vaccine delivers solid protection against HPV.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
