<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Taiwan on Transmission Landscape</title>
    <link>https://haokaitseng.github.io/categories/taiwan/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Taiwan on Transmission Landscape</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>zh-tw</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://haokaitseng.github.io/categories/taiwan/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Agentic AI adoption for app development: Global Outbreak Intelligence Hub</title>
      <link>https://haokaitseng.github.io/post/20260226_global_outbreak_intelligence_antigravity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://haokaitseng.github.io/post/20260226_global_outbreak_intelligence_antigravity/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I’ll share a step-by-step guide on how I leveraged Google Antigravity and Gemini 3.0 model to modernize a mission-critical workflow. This React-based application prototype transforms raw epidemic signals into a seamless, interactive geospatial narrative, reimagining how we visualize global health intelligence. Link to the application Global Outbreak Intelligence Hub and the Github repo&#xA;Step by step guide: Prompt engineering in Antigravity In my first attempt, I manually drafted a Markdown file describing the app&amp;rsquo;s requirements.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The WHO Pandemic Agreement: No True Health Security Without Taiwan</title>
      <link>https://haokaitseng.github.io/post/20250712_pandemic_agreement_including_taiwan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jul 2025 22:11:12 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://haokaitseng.github.io/post/20250712_pandemic_agreement_including_taiwan/</guid>
      <description>I volunteer for the Taiwan Youth Initiatives in Europe (TYIE) and originally published this post on TYIE&amp;rsquo;s website, discussing :&#xA;What is the WHO Pandemic Agreement? Why is the exclusion of Taiwan unjustified? The approval of the World Health Organization (WHO) Pandemic Agreement by the 78th World Health Assembly (WHA) Committee in May marks a landmark global commitment to fortify pandemic prevention, preparedness and response (PPR) capacities. The agreement aims to achieve the common interest of a more equitable and better prepared world to prevent, respond to and recover from pandemics.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
