<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R on Transmission Landscape</title>
    <link>https://haokaitseng.github.io/categories/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R on Transmission Landscape</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>zh-tw</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 22:11:12 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://haokaitseng.github.io/categories/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Co-financing for vaccine portfolio: visual tips and data flow</title>
      <link>https://haokaitseng.github.io/post/20241220-cofinancing-portfolio-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 22:11:12 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://haokaitseng.github.io/post/20241220-cofinancing-portfolio-management/</guid>
      <description>This post shares my work at the lovely Immunisation Financing &amp;amp; Sustainability (IF&amp;amp;S) team at Gavi, the Vaccine Alliance. Please note that views expressed here are my own and don&amp;rsquo;t represent the views of my employer, Gavi. It covers:&#xA;Brief intro for Gavi&amp;rsquo;s Co-financing model 5 visual tips for portfolio management (some with R code), e.g. risk-assessment table and faceted pie An optimized data flow for a complex data ecosystem What is Co-financing Under Gavi&amp;rsquo;s Co-financing policy, countries share the costs of the vaccine programmes by directly co-procuring a portion of the vaccines and injection devices from a supplier or procurement agency to fulfill their co-financing requirements.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mapping the Relationships: Modelling Immunisation Efforts on the Non-Polio Acute Flaccid Paralysis Rate</title>
      <link>https://haokaitseng.github.io/post/20240719_polio_poster_vaccine_hesitancy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 22:11:12 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://haokaitseng.github.io/post/20240719_polio_poster_vaccine_hesitancy/</guid>
      <description>This post shares my poster presentation at the Vaccine Hesitancy Course held by the Croucher Foundation in August, 2024, Hong Kong.&#xA;Download the poster here, which is the milestone of my thesis project at LSHTM. Introduction Global incidence of polio has decreased by 99% since 1988. Non-polio Acute Flaccid Paralysis (NPAFP) is the key indicator for the sensitivity of polio surveillance. While countries with circulating poliovirus consistently report NPAFP rates exceeding the gold-standard indicator*, it is not well-understood what rate should be expected.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Minimizing data linkage error in an ETL pipeline using R: an intersection of MIMIC III and ODK database</title>
      <link>https://haokaitseng.github.io/post/20240101-data-linkage-etl-mimic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2024 22:11:12 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://haokaitseng.github.io/post/20240101-data-linkage-etl-mimic/</guid>
      <description>What can you learn from this article?&#xA;Understand the concepts of data linkage, especially deterministic linakge. Address linkage error in the conjunction of MIMIC III (served in a postgreSQL database) and ODK database. Employ R to design the Extract, Transform, and Load (ETL) pipeline. Use Quarto document to generate a report in PDF format. Concepts of Data Linkage In a data scientist&amp;rsquo;s typical day, the merge/join function is an inevitable task.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
