<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Science on Infectious Perspectives</title>
    <link>https://haokaitseng.github.io/categories/data-science/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Science on Infectious Perspectives</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>zh-tw</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 22:11:12 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://haokaitseng.github.io/categories/data-science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Equity vs. Equality: Modelling Vaccine Distribution in Response to an Influenza Outbreak</title>
      <link>https://haokaitseng.github.io/post/20240327_modelling_flu/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 22:11:12 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://haokaitseng.github.io/post/20240327_modelling_flu/</guid>
      <description>This group project is a collective effort, with contributions from my teammates Minn Thit Aung, Polly Nightingale, Simon Kent, and Xavier Dunn, listed alphabetically.*&#xA;This post aims to:&#xA;Find the the basic reproduction number of an hypothetical outbreak Assess the impact of specified vaccination strategies and school closures on an outbreak Offer codes on creating a GIF of an epidemic curve using R Note that this blog is currently under construction.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Survival Analysis in Electronic Health Records Data</title>
      <link>https://haokaitseng.github.io/post/20240322-survival-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 22:11:12 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://haokaitseng.github.io/post/20240322-survival-analysis/</guid>
      <description>How do you apply time-to-event analysis to compare the impact of different prescriptions on death?&#xA;This article examines the survival function of two prescriptions using Kaplan-Meier and Cox models in an electronic health records (EHR) setting. EHR data are powerful real-world data. They are conducive to time-to-event analysis owing to the characteristic of sequential visits to primary and secondary care services. Take UK&amp;rsquo;s OpenSAFELY for instance, this secure, transparent, and open-source platform provides an Trusted Research Environment (TRE) for National Health Service (NHS) EHR data analysis, which supported urgent research into the COVID-19 emergency.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Predicting Remission Status in Healthcare: A Comparative Analysis of Lasso, Random Forest, and Adaboost Machine Learning Models</title>
      <link>https://haokaitseng.github.io/post/20240210-machine-learning-lasso-random-forest/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2024 22:11:12 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://haokaitseng.github.io/post/20240210-machine-learning-lasso-random-forest/</guid>
      <description>In this article, we will explore the following topics:&#xA;Using regularized method (Lasso) for predictive variable selection Tuning hyperparameters for tree-based methods Employing the weighted sum of weak learners for boosted classifier Comparing prediction performances and predictors importance Basic Methods Inmagine you possess a dataset comprising 30 biomarker varaibles with 5000+. How would you use it to predict patient&amp;rsquo;s remission status, i.e. remission or active disease? One common approach that may cross your mind is the logistic regression, as illustrated below:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Minimizing data linkage error in an ETL pipeline using R: an intersection of MIMIC III and ODK database</title>
      <link>https://haokaitseng.github.io/post/20240101-data-linkage-etl-mimic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2024 22:11:12 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://haokaitseng.github.io/post/20240101-data-linkage-etl-mimic/</guid>
      <description>What can you learn from this article?&#xA;Understand the concepts of data linkage, especially deterministic linakge. Address linkage error in the conjunction of MIMIC III (served in a postgreSQL database) and ODK database. Employ R to design the Extract, Transform, and Load (ETL) pipeline. Use Quarto document to generate a report in PDF format. Concepts of Data Linkage In a data scientist&amp;rsquo;s typical day, the merge/join function is an inevitable task.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing Data Protection: Leveraging Information Governance Principles from GDPR into Research Planning</title>
      <link>https://haokaitseng.github.io/post/20231030-data-governance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2023 22:11:12 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://haokaitseng.github.io/post/20231030-data-governance/</guid>
      <description>This article delivers two key insights:&#xA;Advantages of applying UK GDPR in research planning. Five approaches to safeguard data protection in lung cancer patient interviews. Setting th Scene The need of assessing the Quality of Life (QoL) in patients with lung cancer undergoing chemotherapy has been increasing. After treatment, patients may experience breathlessness or fatigue, along with potential challenges in their daily and occupational functioning. These side effects of chemotherapy consistently rank as a common complaint among patients.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Navigating Short-Term Accommodation Search in London</title>
      <link>https://haokaitseng.github.io/post/20230907london-rent-cost/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2023 22:11:12 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://haokaitseng.github.io/post/20230907london-rent-cost/</guid>
      <description>This year, London home rental prices hit record as demand outstriped supply, with the average tenant now being asked to pay a whopping £2,500 a month for a new let.&#xA;Within this rental market, individuals seeking short-term accommodations encounter greater challenges. My roommates and I was looking for a house/flat for co-renting with a 6-month tenancy, and we put in a significant effort throughout the entire month of August by searching and making inquiries about over 170 properties before finally settling down.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
