<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Science on Transmission Landscape</title>
    <link>https://haokaitseng.github.io/categories/data-science/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Science on Transmission Landscape</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>zh-tw</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://haokaitseng.github.io/categories/data-science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Agentic AI adoption for app development: Global Outbreak Intelligence Hub</title>
      <link>https://haokaitseng.github.io/post/20260226_global_outbreak_intelligence_antigravity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://haokaitseng.github.io/post/20260226_global_outbreak_intelligence_antigravity/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I’ll share a step-by-step guide on how I leveraged Google Antigravity and Gemini 3.0 model to modernize a mission-critical workflow. This React-based application prototype transforms raw epidemic signals into a seamless, interactive geospatial narrative, reimagining how we visualize global health intelligence. Link to the application Global Outbreak Intelligence Hub and the Github repo&#xA;Step by step guide: Prompt engineering in Antigravity In my first attempt, I manually drafted a Markdown file describing the app&amp;rsquo;s requirements.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-sustained data &amp; measures in Power BI</title>
      <link>https://haokaitseng.github.io/post/20250313_powerbi_sustained_data_updating/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 22:11:12 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://haokaitseng.github.io/post/20250313_powerbi_sustained_data_updating/</guid>
      <description>This post aims to advance your Power BI skills by:&#xA;Creating a sequence of sustained measures in a new table, rather than having random measures co-existing with variables. Updating longitudinal data when new data is routinely received. [Note that the data used in this post are examples, inspired by my work with the Immunisation Financing &amp;amp; Sustainability (IF&amp;amp;S) team at Gavi. The views expressed here are my own and do not represent those of my former employer, Gavi.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Co-financing for vaccine portfolio: visual tips and data flow</title>
      <link>https://haokaitseng.github.io/post/20241220-cofinancing-portfolio-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 22:11:12 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://haokaitseng.github.io/post/20241220-cofinancing-portfolio-management/</guid>
      <description>This post shares my work at the lovely Immunisation Financing &amp;amp; Sustainability (IF&amp;amp;S) team at Gavi, the Vaccine Alliance. Please note that views expressed here are my own and don&amp;rsquo;t represent the views of my employer, Gavi. It covers:&#xA;Brief intro for Gavi&amp;rsquo;s Co-financing model 5 visual tips for portfolio management (some with R code), e.g. risk-assessment table and faceted pie An optimized data flow for a complex data ecosystem What is Co-financing Under Gavi&amp;rsquo;s Co-financing policy, countries share the costs of the vaccine programmes by directly co-procuring a portion of the vaccines and injection devices from a supplier or procurement agency to fulfill their co-financing requirements.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mapping the Relationships: Modelling Immunisation Efforts on the Non-Polio Acute Flaccid Paralysis Rate</title>
      <link>https://haokaitseng.github.io/post/20240719_polio_poster_vaccine_hesitancy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 22:11:12 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://haokaitseng.github.io/post/20240719_polio_poster_vaccine_hesitancy/</guid>
      <description>This post shares my poster presentation at the Vaccine Hesitancy Course held by the Croucher Foundation in August, 2024, Hong Kong.&#xA;Download the poster here, which is the milestone of my thesis project at LSHTM. Introduction Global incidence of polio has decreased by 99% since 1988. Non-polio Acute Flaccid Paralysis (NPAFP) is the key indicator for the sensitivity of polio surveillance. While countries with circulating poliovirus consistently report NPAFP rates exceeding the gold-standard indicator*, it is not well-understood what rate should be expected.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My MSc Journey at LSHTM</title>
      <link>https://haokaitseng.github.io/post/20240614_hdsplaylist_vacfocus/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 22:11:12 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://haokaitseng.github.io/post/20240614_hdsplaylist_vacfocus/</guid>
      <description>This post shares my two publications at LSHTM, showcasing my two student roles and achievements:&#xA;Student and Digital Content Ambassador Student Liason Officer at the Vaccine Centre Songs That Accompany Our Study In this blog post, I share the diverse music landscape shaped by my MSc Health Data Science classmates from across the globe. This post is also being highlighted on the World Music Day, 21th June 2024, by the LHSTM channel of Instagram and Facebook.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Where COVID Has Shifted Flu and RSV Seasons</title>
      <link>https://haokaitseng.github.io/post/20240514_sanofi_think_global_health/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 22:11:12 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://haokaitseng.github.io/post/20240514_sanofi_think_global_health/</guid>
      <description>This post shares a publication on Think Global Health, showcasing collaborative efforts with my teammamtes: Wan-Jen Lee, Giovanni Jacob, Dhihram Tenrisau, and Caitlynne McGaff.&#xA;Read our article by navitagting to Think Global Health. Data Visualisations Epicurve in England This graph has been recreated by Editor Allison Krugman.&#xA;Selected Heatmaps Heatmaps showing the log hospitalization rates for influenza and RSV throughout each season. Darker shades means higher hospitalization rate. This graph has been recreated by Editor Allison Krugman.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Beginnig of the End: What Is the Expected Notification Rate of the Polio Surveillance Indicator?</title>
      <link>https://haokaitseng.github.io/post/20240503_polio_proposal/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 22:11:12 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://haokaitseng.github.io/post/20240503_polio_proposal/</guid>
      <description>This post presents my research proposal for my MSc thesis: &amp;ldquo;Predicting the rate of Acute Flaccid Paralysis in different settings to support polio surveillance and elimination&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;You will learn why non-polio Acute Flaccid Paralysis (NPAFP) is important in support of polio eradication. The current challenge involves interpreting the AFP indicator that exceed the targeted levels. Potential data sources and modelling methods are raised to fill this knowledge gap. Aim and Objectives Research Aim To investigate and model the mechanisms underlying the notification of the key polio surveillance indicator - NPAFP rates in endemic and outbreak settings.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Equity vs. Equality: Modelling Vaccine Distribution Strategies for Outbreak Response Decision-Making</title>
      <link>https://haokaitseng.github.io/post/20240327_modelling_flu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2024 22:11:12 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://haokaitseng.github.io/post/20240327_modelling_flu/</guid>
      <description>This group project is a collective effort, with contributions from my teammates Minn Thit Aung, Polly Nightingale, Simon Kent, and Xavier Dunn, listed alphabetically.&#xA;This post aims to:&#xA;Determine the the basic reproduction number (R0) of an hypothetical outbreak Assess the impact of various strategies for vaccination and school closures on accumulative cases and peak cases/timing Provide instructions for constructing a SEIR model using Berkeley Madonna Offer simple R code for converting a ggplot into a GIF Setting the Scene Many countries have recently experienced the first wave of an influenza pandemic caused by the strain HuNz.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Survival Analysis in Electronic Health Records Data</title>
      <link>https://haokaitseng.github.io/post/20240322-survival-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 22:11:12 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://haokaitseng.github.io/post/20240322-survival-analysis/</guid>
      <description>How do you apply time-to-event analysis to compare the impact of different prescriptions on death?&#xA;This article examines the survival function of two prescriptions using Kaplan-Meier and Cox models in an electronic health records (EHR) setting. EHR data are powerful real-world data. They are conducive to time-to-event analysis owing to the characteristic of sequential visits to primary and secondary care services. Take UK&amp;rsquo;s OpenSAFELY for instance, this secure, transparent, and open-source platform provides an Trusted Research Environment (TRE) for National Health Service (NHS) EHR data analysis, which supported urgent research into the COVID-19 emergency.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Predicting Remission Status in Healthcare: A Comparative Analysis of Lasso, Random Forest, and Adaboost Machine Learning Models</title>
      <link>https://haokaitseng.github.io/post/20240210-machine-learning-lasso-random-forest/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2024 22:11:12 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://haokaitseng.github.io/post/20240210-machine-learning-lasso-random-forest/</guid>
      <description>In this article, we will explore the following topics:&#xA;Using regularized method (Lasso) for predictive variable selection Tuning hyperparameters for tree-based methods Employing the weighted sum of weak learners for boosted classifier Comparing prediction performances and predictors importance Basic Methods Inmagine you possess a dataset comprising 30 biomarker varaibles with 5000+. How would you use it to predict patient&amp;rsquo;s remission status, i.e. remission or active disease? One common approach that may cross your mind is the logistic regression, as illustrated below:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Minimizing data linkage error in an ETL pipeline using R: an intersection of MIMIC III and ODK database</title>
      <link>https://haokaitseng.github.io/post/20240101-data-linkage-etl-mimic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2024 22:11:12 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://haokaitseng.github.io/post/20240101-data-linkage-etl-mimic/</guid>
      <description>What can you learn from this article?&#xA;Understand the concepts of data linkage, especially deterministic linakge. Address linkage error in the conjunction of MIMIC III (served in a postgreSQL database) and ODK database. Employ R to design the Extract, Transform, and Load (ETL) pipeline. Use Quarto document to generate a report in PDF format. Concepts of Data Linkage In a data scientist&amp;rsquo;s typical day, the merge/join function is an inevitable task.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing Data Protection: Leveraging Information Governance Principles from GDPR into Research Planning</title>
      <link>https://haokaitseng.github.io/post/20231030-data-governance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2023 22:11:12 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://haokaitseng.github.io/post/20231030-data-governance/</guid>
      <description>This article delivers two key insights:&#xA;Advantages of applying UK GDPR in research planning. Five approaches to safeguard data protection in lung cancer patient interviews. Setting th Scene The need of assessing the Quality of Life (QoL) in patients with lung cancer undergoing chemotherapy has been increasing. After treatment, patients may experience breathlessness or fatigue, along with potential challenges in their daily and occupational functioning. These side effects of chemotherapy consistently rank as a common complaint among patients.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Navigating Short-Term Accommodation Search in London</title>
      <link>https://haokaitseng.github.io/post/20230907london-rent-cost/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2023 22:11:12 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://haokaitseng.github.io/post/20230907london-rent-cost/</guid>
      <description>This year, London home rental prices hit record as demand outstriped supply, with the average tenant now being asked to pay a whopping £2,500 a month for a new let.&#xA;Within this rental market, individuals seeking short-term accommodations encounter greater challenges. My roommates and I was looking for a house/flat for co-renting with a 6-month tenancy, and we put in a significant effort throughout the entire month of August by searching and making inquiries about over 170 properties before finally settling down.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
