<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Visualisation on Transmission Landscape</title>
    <link>https://haokaitseng.github.io/categories/visualisation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Visualisation on Transmission Landscape</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>zh-tw</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 22:11:12 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://haokaitseng.github.io/categories/visualisation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Co-financing for vaccine portfolio: visual tips and data flow</title>
      <link>https://haokaitseng.github.io/post/20241220-cofinancing-portfolio-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 22:11:12 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://haokaitseng.github.io/post/20241220-cofinancing-portfolio-management/</guid>
      <description>This post shares my work at the lovely Immunisation Financing &amp;amp; Sustainability (IF&amp;amp;S) team at Gavi, the Vaccine Alliance. Please note that views expressed here are my own and don&amp;rsquo;t represent the views of my employer, Gavi. It covers:&#xA;Brief intro for Gavi&amp;rsquo;s Co-financing model 5 visual tips for portfolio management (some with R code), e.g. risk-assessment table and faceted pie An optimized data flow for a complex data ecosystem What is Co-financing Under Gavi&amp;rsquo;s Co-financing policy, countries share the costs of the vaccine programmes by directly co-procuring a portion of the vaccines and injection devices from a supplier or procurement agency to fulfill their co-financing requirements.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Where COVID Has Shifted Flu and RSV Seasons</title>
      <link>https://haokaitseng.github.io/post/20240514_sanofi_think_global_health/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 22:11:12 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://haokaitseng.github.io/post/20240514_sanofi_think_global_health/</guid>
      <description>This post shares a publication on Think Global Health, showcasing collaborative efforts with my teammamtes: Wan-Jen Lee, Giovanni Jacob, Dhihram Tenrisau, and Caitlynne McGaff.&#xA;Read our article by navitagting to Think Global Health. Data Visualisations Epicurve in England This graph has been recreated by Editor Allison Krugman.&#xA;Selected Heatmaps Heatmaps showing the log hospitalization rates for influenza and RSV throughout each season. Darker shades means higher hospitalization rate. This graph has been recreated by Editor Allison Krugman.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
